<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflows on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflows on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes I take notes to support reference, recollection, and accumulation. This approach was heavily influenced by Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s concept of Evergreen Notes.
Reference The best reference for learning something is usually not the most useful for applying it. I learned about random walks from the Feynman Lectures, but when I need to calculate diffusion coefficients I reference a note that just gives the answer and a few supporting details.
Reference notes should be optimized for frequently, repeated use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prioritization</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/prioritization/</guid>
      <description>Prioritization Picking the right ideas to work on is important.
When I was an academic, I wrote ideas in Markdown notes with one top-level header per idea. To decide what to work on, I used a python script which asks me to compare ideas to one another. The comparison questions are:
 If both ideas work, what is their relative impact? What are the relative odds of the ideas working? How long will each idea take to implement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/spacedrepetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/spacedrepetition/</guid>
      <description>Spaced Repetition Spaced repetition is a technique for remembering information over long time periods. It takes advantage of the empirical observation that the time it takes to forget a fact is proportional to the time that fact is known. This suggests that the best strategy to remember something indefinitely is to review facts with ever-larger (geometrically increasing) gaps between reviews. Following that strategy, a finite number of reviews is needed to remember something for the rest of your life, and that number is small enough that the study time needed to remember a fact indefinitely is about 5 minutes, so long as the studying happens in this spaced-out way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Feedback Getting things right without feedback is really hard, so getting frequent and meaningful feedback is important. I do this by asking others for feedback and by looking back at how past work has gone.
Asking Others Giving good feedback is hard. When I ask for feedback I try to make it easier by making it clear what I want feedback on, and by being as specific as possible. So feedback on specific projects or interactions is often better than feedback on &amp;ldquo;my job in general&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/tools/</guid>
      <description>Tools Tools should make work easier, more effective, and more fun.
This is an incomplete list of the tools I use, along with commentary on why I use them.
Computers/OS To help with work/life balance I use two computers, one for work and one for everything else. Both are Macbook Pro&amp;rsquo;s running macOS, one is 15&amp;quot; (work) and the other is 16&amp;quot; (other).
Because Tools Should Express Values I used GeekTool to display a list of values over my desktop background (but below all windows).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
