<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>http://adamjermyn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:52:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://adamjermyn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/workflow/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/workflow/notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes I take notes to support reference, recollection, and accumulation. This approach was heavily influenced by Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s concept of Evergreen Notes.
Reference The best reference for learning something is usually not the most useful for applying it. I learned about random walks from the Feynman Lectures, but when I need to calculate diffusion coefficients I reference a note that just gives the answer and a few supporting details.
Reference notes should be optimized for frequently, repeated use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prioritization</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/workflow/prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/workflow/prioritization/</guid>
      <description>Prioritization Picking the right ideas to work on is important.
I write ideas in Markdown notes with one top-level header per idea. To decide what to work on, I use a python script which asks me to compare ideas to one another. The comparison questions are:
 If both ideas work, what is their relative impact? What are the relative odds of the ideas working? How long will each idea take to implement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Scales for Living on Mars</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:52:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_scales/</guid>
      <description>Mass Scales for Living on Mars Big thanks to Casey Handmer for reading and commenting on an early draft of this.
One of the most exciting things that may well happen this century is a sustained human presence on Mars. The main reason this is possible at all is that SpaceX has cut launch costs dramatically. Despite this progress, cargo sent from Earth and soft-landed on Mars is likely to be the primary resource constraint in the Martian economy for a very long time, so it is worth exploring the scale of cargo required to support a human presence, and what that translated into in dollars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/workflow/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/workflow/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Feedback Getting things right without feedback is really hard, so getting frequent and meaningful feedback is important. I do this by asking others for feedback and by looking back at how past work has gone.
Asking Others Giving good feedback is hard. When I ask for feedback I try to make it easier by making it clear what I want feedback on, and by being as specific as possible. So feedback on specific projects or interactions is often better than feedback on &amp;ldquo;my job in general&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
