<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>https://adamjermyn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:03:20 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamjermyn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes I take notes to support reference, recollection, and accumulation. This approach was heavily influenced by Andy Matuschak&amp;rsquo;s concept of Evergreen Notes.
Reference The best reference for learning something is usually not the most useful for applying it. I learned about random walks from the Feynman Lectures, but when I need to calculate diffusion coefficients I reference a note that just gives the answer and a few supporting details.
Reference notes should be optimized for frequently, repeated use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prioritization</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/prioritization/</guid>
      <description>Prioritization Picking the right ideas to work on is important.
I write ideas in Markdown notes with one top-level header per idea. To decide what to work on, I use a python script which asks me to compare ideas to one another. The comparison questions are:
 If both ideas work, what is their relative impact? What are the relative odds of the ideas working? How long will each idea take to implement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaced Repetition</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/spacedrepetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/spacedrepetition/</guid>
      <description>Spaced Repetition Spaced repetition is a technique for remembering information over long time periods. It takes advantage of the empirical observation that the time it takes to forget a fact is proportional to the time that fact is known. This suggests that the best strategy to remember something indefinitely is to review facts with ever-larger (geometrically increasing) gaps between reviews. Following that strategy, a finite number of reviews is needed to remember something for the rest of your life, and that number is small enough that the study time needed to remember a fact indefinitely is about 5 minutes, so long as the studying happens in this spaced-out way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Riboflavin prevent Migraines?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/riboflavin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:03:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/riboflavin/</guid>
      <description>Abstract (This is not medical advice. I am not a medical professional.)
Supplementing with Riboflavin (Vitamin B2) seems probably helpful for headaches and migraines, likely reducing their frequency by about 50% as well as reducing severity somewhat. This is backed by multiple randomized controlled trials, and I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to check for anything funny in those trials (small samples, weird controls, etc.). The samples tend to be a little small, but not ridiculously so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Value Low-Probability Options Abound</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mugged_by_probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 07:16:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mugged_by_probability/</guid>
      <description>(Numbers in this post are made up to illustrate a point. Likewise the plot device need not be cryptocurrencies, that&amp;rsquo;s just flavor text.)
You&amp;rsquo;re walking on the street, minding your business. Suddenly, a stranger (S) comes up and starts talking to you:
 S: Have you heard? There&amp;rsquo;s a one-in-a-million chance you could save a billion lives! All you have to do is found a crypto currency, become extremely rich, and use that money to fight Malaria!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID Testing - Sensitivity and Timelines</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/covid_testing_timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 10:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/covid_testing_timing/</guid>
      <description>COVID Testing - Sensitivity and Timelines This past week a close contact had a potential COVID exposure, so I wanted to understand a few basic questions about COVID testing to help figure out what is safe and what isn&amp;rsquo;t. Three questions seem especially relevant:
 How sensitive are PCR and rapid antigen tests? If someone tests negative on a rapid antigen test but positive on PCR, should they worry about infecting other people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A School for Agency</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/agency_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 14:42:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/agency_school/</guid>
      <description>A School for Agency Agency is where you act to achieve your goals. It&amp;rsquo;s where you look at problems and say &amp;ldquo;How could I solve them?&amp;rdquo; and really think about that and arrive at possible courses of action and then take those actions. Explicitly, agency is about executing three steps:
 Notice a problem/question. Brainstorm solutions. Try solutions until something works or the costs exceed the benefits.  An example I return to often in the summer is air conditioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Project Reviews</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/automated_reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 15:04:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/automated_reviews/</guid>
      <description>Automated Project Reviews Getting things right without feedback is really hard, but not all feedback comes from other people! One quick way to generate meaningful feedback is by looking back at past work.
A challenge with looking back is doing it at the right time. For some kinds of feedback this is easy: schedule weekly/monthly/quarterly reviews, with prompts tuned to the relevant time-scale. But some areas of life don&amp;rsquo;t run on a regular schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toy Model of Near-Existential Risk</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/near_existential_risk_pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 16:05:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/near_existential_risk_pt2/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote about near-existential risk. These are risks which result in massive losses to society of people/technology/capability, but which themselves do not actually end or permanently curtail human existence. Here I want to build a toy model for thinking about these risks and how they relate to actual existential risks.
A Toy Model For these purposes I&amp;rsquo;m going to reduce the many dimensions of loss to a single parameter $\ell$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-Existential Risk</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/near_existential_risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 16:17:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/near_existential_risk/</guid>
      <description>Longtermism is a moral theory that says that most of the value we (humans) ought to care about lies in the future, and so we should look hard for opportunities to influence the future in positive ways. Longtermism arises as a natural consequence of three ideas:
 Utilitarianism: We should improve the lives/subjective wellbeing of as many people as much as possible, evaluated by summing improvements over lives. Future lives are just as valuable as present lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of Tools with Values</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/values_examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/values_examples/</guid>
      <description>I previously argued that tools should express values. Here are some examples of tools I&amp;rsquo;ve made with an eye to values.
A Brainstorming Environment I have a shell script that sets up a work environment for brainstorming. It does this by copying and opening a template text document that says the following:
# Session: - Maintain an attitude of suspended judgement. - You&#39;re here to climb out of the basin. - Cmd+E Will bring up an (incomplete) list of possible approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Food on Mars</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 10:24:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_soil/</guid>
      <description>Growing food on Mars is a critical component of making a self-sufficient city because shipping food is expensive.
Unfortunately it seems that Martian regolith is too alkaline and is missing key nutrients needed to grow crops. The alkaline issue can be solved by adding acid, which is both low-weight and can be produced locally if need be. The nutrient issue can be addressed either by adding organic material or by artificial nutrient supplementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Martian Software</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:29:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_software/</guid>
      <description>Building a city on Mars will be very capital intensive because in the early stages it&amp;rsquo;s extremely expensive to sustain people on Mars. But capital is a vague term: what does this actually look like?
The last few attempts at a human presence in space primarily used physical capital: heavy machinery, giant rockets and space stations and industrial equipment. Mars will need all of that too. But the last few times were in the 1960s-90s, when computers were slow and software much more limited and expensive than today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Tools</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/robust_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:37:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/robust_tools/</guid>
      <description>Good tools are robust. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t just mean that they don&amp;rsquo;t fail, it means that in many instances they can&amp;rsquo;t fail. They take common failure modes off the table, freeing you to use them and focus on your goals.
Impossible Failure Modes For a robust tool many failure modes are, by design, simply impossible, to the point where it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine what those failure modes are.
Consider a solid metal hammer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools Should Express Values</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/tools_values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 15:56:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/tools_values/</guid>
      <description>I want my tools to express values. I want my text editor to tell me to write clearly. I want my scientific software to command me “Be true, be open, be humble, be curious.” I want tools to be less blank pages and more pleas for me to honor the values of the craft.
Blank is not Neutral Many tools today are designed like blank pages. A writing app has a large blank space, with perhaps a few buttons for changing fonts and an indicator of how many words are on the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth and Population on Mars</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/alpha_beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 11:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/alpha_beta/</guid>
      <description>Economies of Scale I previously wrote about a simple model of an early Martain economy. A key input to that model is the way that human productivity scales with population and investment. I captured this with the simple scaling $$ p \propto I^\alpha n^\beta $$ for $\alpha,\beta &amp;gt; 0$. This relation says that the per-person productivity $p$ scales as some positive power $\alpha$ of the per-person investment $I$, which could reflect machinery or materials or personnel support from Earth, and as another positive power $\beta$ of the number of people $n$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Economic Model of Martian Growth</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:33:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_economy/</guid>
      <description>An Economic Model of Martian Growth Mars is an expensive place to live, but it rapidly becomes cheaper the more infrastructure it has! Because of that the total cost of building a self-sufficient city on Mars depends on how quickly infrastructure can be built. This is the key question I want to understand: what is the best way to invest in Martian infrastructure that minimizes the total cost?
A Simple Model To do this I&amp;rsquo;ll build a simple model of economic growth on Mars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Scales for Living on Mars</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:52:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_scales/</guid>
      <description>Mass Scales for Living on Mars Big thanks to Casey Handmer for reading and commenting on an early draft of this.
One of the most exciting things that may well happen this century is a sustained human presence on Mars. The main reason this is possible at all is that SpaceX has cut launch costs dramatically. Despite this progress, cargo sent from Earth and soft-landed on Mars is likely to be the primary resource constraint in the Martian economy for a very long time, so it is worth exploring the scale of cargo required to support a human presence, and what that translated into in dollars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/feedback/</guid>
      <description>Feedback Getting things right without feedback is really hard, so getting frequent and meaningful feedback is important. I do this by asking others for feedback and by looking back at how past work has gone.
Asking Others Giving good feedback is hard. When I ask for feedback I try to make it easier by making it clear what I want feedback on, and by being as specific as possible. So feedback on specific projects or interactions is often better than feedback on &amp;ldquo;my job in general&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/workflow/tools/</guid>
      <description>Tools Tools should make work easier, more effective, and more fun.
This is an incomplete list of the tools I use, along with commentary on why I use them.
Computers/OS To help with work/life balance I use two computers, one for work and one for everything else. Both are Macbook Pro&amp;rsquo;s running macOS, one is 15&amp;quot; (work) and the other is 16&amp;quot; (other).
I often run calculations on remote machines which I don&amp;rsquo;t manage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
