<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 15:56:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://adamjermyn.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools Should Express Values</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/tools_values/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 15:56:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/tools_values/</guid>
      <description>I want my tools to express values. I want my text editor to tell me to write clearly. I want my scientific software to command me “Be true, be open, be humble, be curious.” I want tools to be less blank pages and more pleas for me to honor the values of the craft.
Blank is not Neutral Many tools today are designed like blank pages. A writing app has a large blank space, with perhaps a few buttons for changing fonts and an indicator of how many words are on the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth and Population on Mars</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/alpha_beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 11:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/alpha_beta/</guid>
      <description>Economies of Scale I previously wrote about a simple model of an early Martain economy. A key input to that model is the way that human productivity scales with population and investment. I captured this with the simple scaling $$ p \propto I^\alpha n^\beta $$ for $\alpha,\beta &amp;gt; 0$. This relation says that the per-person productivity $p$ scales as some positive power $\alpha$ of the per-person investment $I$, which could reflect machinery or materials or personnel support from Earth, and as another positive power $\beta$ of the number of people $n$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Economic Model of Martian Growth</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:33:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_economy/</guid>
      <description>An Economic Model of Martian Growth Mars is an expensive place to live, but it rapidly becomes cheaper the more infrastructure it has! Because of that the total cost of building a self-sufficient city on Mars depends on how quickly infrastructure can be built. This is the key question I want to understand: what is the best way to invest in Martian infrastructure that minimizes the total cost?
A Simple Model To do this I&amp;rsquo;ll build a simple model of economic growth on Mars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Scales for Living on Mars</title>
      <link>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:52:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamjermyn.com/posts/mars_scales/</guid>
      <description>Mass Scales for Living on Mars Big thanks to Casey Handmer for reading and commenting on an early draft of this.
One of the most exciting things that may well happen this century is a sustained human presence on Mars. The main reason this is possible at all is that SpaceX has cut launch costs dramatically. Despite this progress, cargo sent from Earth and soft-landed on Mars is likely to be the primary resource constraint in the Martian economy for a very long time, so it is worth exploring the scale of cargo required to support a human presence, and what that translated into in dollars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
