<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agency on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>https://adamjermyn.com/tags/agency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agency on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 09:01:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamjermyn.com/tags/agency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Agency</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/agency_social/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 09:01:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/agency_social/</guid>
      <description>Agency is where you act to achieve your goals. Unfortunately agency is hard and not the default state.
Social nudging is a powerful way to combat this. Here are a few lightly-edited conversations that I&amp;rsquo;ve observed or participated in that pushed towards more agency:
Fire  P1: There&amp;rsquo;s a fire ~20 miles away and it&amp;rsquo;s raining ash.
P2: Do you have an air purifier?
P1: &amp;hellip; no, I should get one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Riboflavin Prevent Migraines?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/riboflavin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:03:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/riboflavin/</guid>
      <description>Abstract (This is not medical advice. I am not a medical professional. Thanks to Rose DiLoreto for the idea for this post.)
Supplementing with Riboflavin (Vitamin B2) seems probably helpful for headaches and migraines, likely reducing their frequency by about 50% as well as reducing severity somewhat. This is backed by multiple randomized controlled trials, and I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to check for anything funny in those trials (small samples, weird controls, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Value Low-Probability Options Abound</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mugged_by_probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 07:16:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/mugged_by_probability/</guid>
      <description>(Numbers in this post are made up to illustrate a point. Likewise the plot device need not be cryptocurrencies, that&amp;rsquo;s just flavor text.)
You&amp;rsquo;re walking on the street, minding your business. Suddenly, a stranger (S) comes up and starts talking to you:
 S: Have you heard? There&amp;rsquo;s a one-in-a-million chance you could save a billion lives! All you have to do is found a crypto currency, become extremely rich, and use that money to fight Malaria!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A School for Agency</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/agency_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 14:42:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/agency_school/</guid>
      <description>A School for Agency Agency is where you act to achieve your goals. It&amp;rsquo;s where you look at problems and say &amp;ldquo;How could I solve them?&amp;rdquo; and really think about that and arrive at possible courses of action and then take those actions. Explicitly, agency is about executing three steps:
 Notice a problem/question. Brainstorm solutions. Try solutions until something works or the costs exceed the benefits.  An example I return to often in the summer is air conditioning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
