<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astronomy on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>https://adamjermyn.com/tags/astronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astronomy on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:40:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamjermyn.com/tags/astronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Mixing on Tayler Columns</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 13:40:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas27/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the 27th post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated.
Chemical Mixing on Tayler Columns What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? In rapidly rotating stars and planets convection forms narrow columns. Mixing is rapid along the column but slow across columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium Flash and Surface Effects</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 11:42:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas26/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the 26th post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated. This idea is based on work I did with Jim Fuller.
Helium Flash and Surface Effects What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Stars below around $3 M_\odot$ exhibit a helium flash, in which degenerate helium in their cores ignites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overshooting at low Péclet number</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 09:53:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas25/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the 25th post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated. This idea is based on discussions and calculations with Matteo Cantiello, Daniel Lecoanet, Evan Anders, Eoin Farrell, Yan-Fei Jiang, Lars Bildsten, and Will Schultz.
Overshooting at low Péclet number What&amp;rsquo;s the idea?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What saturates the centrifugal instability?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 10:55:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas24/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the 24th post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated. This idea is based on a paper by Xihui Zhao and Jim Fuller.
What saturates the centrifugal instability? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? The centrifugal instability is a linear instability (section 4) caused by the centrifugal force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can waves advect magnetic fields?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 11:52:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/ideas23/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the 23rd post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated. This idea is closely related to conversations I once had with Dong Lai.
Can waves advect magnetic fields? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? The electrical conductivity in stars is enormous, so the magnetic diffusivity is small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do stars evolve in molecular clouds?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 08:18:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas21/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the 21st post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated.
How do stars evolve in molecular clouds? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Some stars are in molecular clouds, and the clouds probably affect their evolution by blocking escaping light, exerting pressure on their surfaces, possibly accreting mass onto their surfaces, coupling to their rotation via magnetic fields, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black holes in gas clouds</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 07:25:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas20/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the twentieth post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated. This idea emerged from a conversation with Yuri Levin.
Black holes in gas clouds What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Asa black hole moves through a gas cloud it should drag on the gas, depositing kinetic energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do magnetic fields slow accretion onto AGN stars?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 09:20:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas19/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don’t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the nineteenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I’ve accumulated. This idea was suggested to me by Yuri Levin and I&amp;rsquo;ve just fleshed it out a little below.
Do magnetic fields slow accretion onto AGN stars?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave Heating and F-type Stars</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 12:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas18/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the eighteenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Wave Heating and F-type Stars What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Convection zones emit internal gravity waves at their boundaries. There is some uncertainty as to exactly how much power escapes in these waves, but estimates are of order $L_{\rm conv}\mathcal{M}$, where $L_{\rm conv}$ is the heat carried by convection and $\mathcal{M}$ is the convective Mach number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential rotation in stars and planetary orbits</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 11:01:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas17/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the seventeenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Differential rotation in stars and planetary orbits What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Stars exhibit differential rotation. At the same time, tides tend to bring stellar rotation rates and planetary orbits closer together in period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can LISA see stellar convection?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 09:30:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas16/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the sixteenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Can LISA see stellar convection? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Convection in stars produces density fluctuations, resulting in a change in the quadrupole moment. This effect should be of order the square of the convective Mach number (which controls density fluctuations).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much material do AGN stars re-accrete?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 10:41:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas15/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the fifteenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
How much material do AGN stars re-accrete? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Stellar evolution in AGN disks is expected to produce massive stars that exist in a balance between wind mass loss and accretion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are stars in the galactic center related to the prior AGN phase?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 09:24:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas14/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the fourteenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
How are stars in the galactic center related to the prior AGN phase? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? We think the Milky Way used to host an AGN disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can accretion push RGB stars onto the Main-Sequence?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:17:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas13/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the thirteenth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Can accretion push RGB stars onto the Main-Sequence? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Stars enter the Red Giant Branch (RGB) when they exhaust hydrogen in their cores. Mixing hydrogen-rich material into their cores should reverse this transition, pushing them back onto the main-sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What would happen if two AGN stars merged?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 07:21:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas12/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the twelfth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
What would happen if two AGN stars merged? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? We think that stars in AGN disks live in a balance between accretion and radiation-driven mass-loss, and that this is a stable equilibrium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does turbulence change nuclear burning in stars?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:19:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas11/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the eleventh post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Does turbulence change nuclear burning in stars? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Nuclear burning rates are exponentially sensitive to temperature. Stellar models calculate the mean temperature at each point in a star, but there can be fluctuations about this mean due to turbulent motions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the core convective dipole align with rotation?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 08:11:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas9/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the ninth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Does the core convective dipole align with rotation? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? I&amp;rsquo;m struggling to find a reference, but a recent result out of convection simulations in fully spherical domains is that the dominant flow pattern is a dipole (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do pulsating stars reveal inhibited convection?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 09:34:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas8/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the eighth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Do pulsating stars reveal inhibited convection? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Many A/B stars have pulsations driven by the $\kappa$-mechanism. In these stars, the pulsation often interacts with near-surface convective layers, motivating tools like time-dependent convection theories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lensing from compact remnants in the Galactic Center</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 08:54:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas7/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the seventh post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Lensing from compact remnants in the Galactic Center What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? It&amp;rsquo;s thought that the Milky Way used to host an AGN disk. AGN disks likely contain many stars, and those stars very preferentially evolve into black holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical limits on extreme baseline optical interferometry</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 07:25:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas6/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the sixth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Theoretical limits on extreme baseline optical interferometry What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Interferometry let&amp;rsquo;s you build a giant &amp;lsquo;virtual telescope&amp;rsquo; out of lots of small telescopes. The effective baseline is the longest distance between telescopes, and the number of pixels of effective resolution is roughly the number of telescopes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the Parker mechanism spin down AGN stars?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 07:15:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas5/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the fifth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Does the Parker mechanism spin down AGN stars? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Collaborators and I previously predicted that stars embedded in AGN disks should end up spinning really fast (near breakup).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How correlated are the positions of stars?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas4/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the fourth post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
How correlated are the positions of stars? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? Thanks to the Gaia mission, we now have accurate 3D positions for a large number of stars in the galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tight-binding model for cold dense matter</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas3/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the third post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Can an ad-hoc electron binding model fix the low-temperature low-density limit of the Skye EOS? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? The reason that the Skye EOS doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover all temperatures and densities is that it assumes fully ionized matter, which breaks down at low temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does eating planets make stars magnetic?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 12:56:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas2/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the second post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Can planet injestion explain magnetic RGB stars? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? There are some very magnetic Red Giant Branch (RGB) stars, with measured internal fields of order $10^{5-7}\mathrm{G}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutron Stars in AGN Disks</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 07:38:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas1/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. Over the next few months I&amp;rsquo;ll be collecting those notes and posting those ideas here.
The format I&amp;rsquo;ll try to follow is to explain:
 What the idea is. Why I think it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting idea. How I think someone interested in working on the idea could get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos in Stellar Evolution</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/chaos_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 07:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/chaos_stars/</guid>
      <description>Are stars predictable or chaotic?
A system is chaotic if small perturbations grow exponentially with time. This makes chaotic systems unpredictable on long time-scales, because it becomes fine details in the starting conditions come to dominate at long times.
So: are stars predictable or chaotic? As far as I know this is an open question.
There is some sense in which most stars are predictable. They exist near thermal and hydrostatic equilibrium, and they tend to return to equilibrium when perturbed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
