<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astronomy on Adam Jermyn</title>
    <link>https://adamjermyn.com/tags/astronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astronomy on Adam Jermyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:33:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamjermyn.com/tags/astronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy Ideas III - A tight-binding model for cold dense matter</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 16:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas3/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the third post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Can an ad-hoc electron binding model fix the low-temperature low-density limit of the Skye EOS? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? The reason that the Skye EOS doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover all temperatures and densities is that it assumes fully ionized matter, which breaks down at low temperatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy Ideas II - Does eating planets make stars magnetic?</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 12:56:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas2/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. This is the second post in a series describing some of the ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated.
Can planet injestion explain magnetic RGB stars? What&amp;rsquo;s the idea? There are some very magnetic Red Giant Branch (RGB) stars, with measured internal fields of order $10^{5-7}\mathrm{G}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy Ideas I - Neutron Stars in AGN Disks</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 07:38:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/astroideas1/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes have research ideas that I think are cool, but that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to pursue. I generally just make a note of them and move on. Over the next few months I&amp;rsquo;ll be collecting those notes and posting those ideas here.
The format I&amp;rsquo;ll try to follow is to explain:
 What the idea is. Why I think it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting idea. How I think someone interested in working on the idea could get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos in Stellar Evolution</title>
      <link>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/chaos_stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 07:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamjermyn.com/posts/chaos_stars/</guid>
      <description>Are stars predictable or chaotic?
A system is chaotic if small perturbations grow exponentially with time. This makes chaotic systems unpredictable on long time-scales, because it becomes fine details in the starting conditions come to dominate at long times.
So: are stars predictable or chaotic? As far as I know this is an open question.
There is some sense in which most stars are predictable. They exist near thermal and hydrostatic equilibrium, and they tend to return to equilibrium when perturbed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
